Vladyslav Kalashnyk kalashnyk.vlad@gmail.com +38 (067) 297 40 57, tg: @walak321

Professional summary

A Javascript Software Engineer, specializing in Node.js and backend technologies, working in the industry for 6 years. As an experienced team lead, I had success with managing the full cycle of delivery (from initial requirement creation till the deployment to production), with transparency and visibility for the stakeholders. Have a scientific background in Mathematics, which allowed me to develop exceptional problem solving skills.

Professional skills

Programming languages/platforms: Node.js, JavaScript, TypeScript;

Databases: MongoDB, Redis, DynamoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, ElasticSearch;

Web API platforms: Express.js, NestJS, Apollo GraphQL;

Delivery and build tools: AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Webpack, Jenkins, ArgoCD;

Testing tools: Jest, Mocha, Chai, Sinon.js, Karma;

Logging and monitoring tools: DataDog, ELK, CloudWatch; Frontend development platforms: React, Angular, jQuery.

Work experience

Software Engineer at BetterHealthcare

Feb 2022 - Nov 2022

- Built backend solutions in a microservice architecture for an appointment booking application in Healthcare industry;
- Worked and enhanced upon multiple third-party Electronic Medical Record integrations:
- Improved communication between development and Customer Success teams;
- Had an integral role on architecture and platform decisions, and technology used in the project;
- Reshaped delivery and management procedures for the whole project using JIRA as a management tool;
- Introduced regular release cycles as a part of implementation of the regular SCRUM procedures;
- Added visibility and clarity for the future work prioritization, improved on the project documentation.

Technical Team Lead at Xenoss

Feb 2021 – Jan 2022

- Lead a fullstack team (MERN stack) in an AdTech project overviewing all third party integrations with major known media platforms;
- Ensured practical usage of Agile methodology and Scrum ceremonies to provide best incremental enhancements to the product;
- Prioritization, grooming, technical design (with documentation), review and implementation of features;
- Effective communication and collaboration with other squads within the project to deliver complex updates across the whole product;
- Client expectation management and taking responsibility for the full delivery cycle for the team;
- Improved overall technical solution quality, technical debt management;
- Interviewed new team members, generated personal development plans for existing team members.

Software engineer at Brightgrove

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

- Architectural review of the usage of Cloud computing services (AWS);
- Technical support, evaluation of the team processes;
- Research into current cutting-edge technologies required for the project.

Software engineer at Dev.Pro

Jun 2017 - Jul 2020

- Developed a client facing API (powered by AWS Lambda) for an online ordering solution to support both newly created and legacy enterprise level Point of Sale systems;
- Created several microservices monitoring delivery of information between parts of the big ecosystem and health check availability with high load (over million messages in a day);
- Worked on a highly customizable platform that dynamically generates websites for clients to be used by their clientele for online ordering;
- Supported a test suite for all projects, covering functionality with unit and end to end tests;
- Integrated with the biggest food delivery providers in US;
- Managed client expectation both during day to day work and in business trips;
- Provided monitoring and data visualization from system logs (using ELK stack);
- Internal knowledge holding/sharing, interviewed future team members.

Junior software developer at Brander Studio

Aug 2016 - Jun 2017

- Developed a REST API for a mobile application that is used as a booking service and an aggregator of beauty salons, with a complex filtering on geo location, work schedules and masters' availability;
- Worked on a white-label admin panel for beauty salons to manage their occupancy, bookings and gather statistical data;
- Designed a microservice architecture for a web site providing currency exchange, implemented a highly resilient message broking service based on RabbitMQ;
- Developed several simple landing pages.

Education

Master of Mathematics,

2014 - 2016

University of California, Irvine, Department of Mathematics.

Master of Mathematics.

2013 - 2014

V.N. Karazin Kharkiv National University, Kharkiv, Ukraine,

Department of Mechanics and Mathematics, Subdepartment of Functions theory and Functional analysis.

Bachelor of Mathematics,

2009 - 2013

V.N. Karazin Kharkiv National University, Kharkiv, Ukraine,

Department of Mechanics and Mathematics, Subdepartment of Functions theory and Functional analysis.

Languages

English (fluent), Ukrainian (native), Russian (native).